<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math on Nacho Dev Blog!</title>
    <link>https://nachodevblog.com/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in math on Nacho Dev Blog!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 13:09:31 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nachodevblog.com/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TEPREL-1B</title>
      <link>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/teprel-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 13:09:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/teprel-1b/</guid>
      <description>TEPREL-1B is a liquid bi-propellant rocket engine developed by PLD Space, a Spanish company working towards a slot in the micro satellite launchers. This engine will be used in MIURA-1 a suborbital vehicle that will be able to carry a 100kg payload to 153km and also serve as a test bed for several technologies. The availiable specs of the engine are as follows:
 Propellants: Liquid oxigen (LOX) &amp;amp; Rocket grade kerosne (RP1) Engine cycle: Pressure-fed (helium as pressurant) Thrust (sea level): 30kN Burn time: 122 seconds  On top of this, we also know that the vehicle carries 1000l of LOX and 600l of RP1 [1][2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocket nozzle equations - Throat area</title>
      <link>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/rocket-nozzle-equations-throat-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 12:34:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/rocket-nozzle-equations-throat-area/</guid>
      <description>As a rocketry enthusiast, I find it fascinating how rocket engine nozzles work. A while back, I got my hands on a copy of Rocket Propulsion Elements, an in-depth technical book that goes over the ins and outs of rocket propulsion! Chapter 3 focuses on how a nozzle converts the high-pressure low-velocity combustion gases, into a low-pressure fast stream of gas. The fast stream of gases leaving the nozzle is what generates thrust, according to Newton&#39;s third law: for every acting force, there is an opposite force of equal magnitude acting in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray-Cylinder intersection</title>
      <link>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/ray-cylinder-intersection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 20:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nachodevblog.com/posts/ray-cylinder-intersection/</guid>
      <description>For a given cylinder with radius $R$ and height $H$, a ray with origin $P$ and direction $RD$, find the first intersection point $P&#39;$ between the ray and the cylinder.First, I will simplify the problem by flatening the ray (so effectively this becomes a 2D problem). You can understand this as trying to figure out the intersection point between the ray and a slice of the cylinder.$C$ is the slice center: $(Cylinder_x, P_y, Cylinder_z)$</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>